<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[The Film Dream Academy]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[The Film Dream Academy]]></description>
        <link>http://thefilmdreamacademy.com/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 04:21:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://thefilmdreamacademy.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 04:20:16 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Message from Direk Alfredo Ongleo of the short film "Pormalin"]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<iframe src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FY-JNvOzOz4M%3Ffeature%3Doembed&url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DY-JNvOzOz4M&image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FY-JNvOzOz4M%2Fhqdefault.jpg&key=a715cf41cc93453ca338d350cd26f87b&type=text%2Fhtml&schema=youtube" width="640" height="360" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Y-JNvOzOz4M&amp;feature=share</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">d1fbe6bf-9731-4d55-acc9-1f2957d317af</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 11:14:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CINEMALAYA FEATURES CITIZEN JAKE, SMALLER AND SMALLER CIRCLES, AND OTHERS IN INDIE NATION]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>PRESS RELEASE</strong></p>,<p><strong>July 31, 2018</strong></p>,<h1><strong>CINEMALAYA FEATURES CITIZEN JAKE, SMALLER AND SMALLER CIRCLES, AND OTHERS IN INDIE NATION</strong></h1>,<p><strong>THE Cinemalaya's special section Indie Nation will let film enthusiasts cross out the indie films which they may have missed on their regular screening at the cinema from their must-watch checklist. This component of the Cinemalaya Philippine Independent Film Festival features seven indie films that made buzz and gained international recognition.</strong></p>,<p><strong>The featured indie films include: “Citizen Jake” by Mike de Leon; “Chedeng &amp; Apple” by Rae Red and Fatrick Tabada; “Delia And Sammy” by Therese Cayaba; “Gusto Kita With All My Hypothalamus” by Dwein Baltazar; “Mga Mister Ni Rosario” by Alpha Habon; “Smaller And Smaller Circles” by Raya Martin; “Nervous Translation” by Shireen Seno; “Manggagarab (Man With Sickle)” by Kyle Fermindoza; and, “Bomba (The Bomb)” by Ralston Gonzales Jover.</strong></p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/cf2db0ef-a61e-4459-9f95-4839efe17203.jpg">,<p><strong>Directed by Mike De Leon, “Citizen Jake” is a personal saga of a Filipino and his struggles with the contradictions within his own social class and the demands of a dysfunctional political family in a Third World nation. The film features actors Cherie Gil, Dina Bonnevie, Luis Alandy, Gabby Eigenmann, Max Collins, Teroy Guzman, and Nonie Buencamino, with journalist Atom Araullo as Citizen Jake.</strong></p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/5a42514e-d778-439d-bf99-6bf6452cdd13.jpg">,<p><strong>“Chedeng &amp; Apple,” which is co-directed by Rae Red and Fatrick Tabada, is a comic film about two friends who are both in their 60s. In the wake of her husband's death, 66-yeard-old Chedeng decides to come out of the closet, while her 63-year-old best friend Apple beheads her live-in partner in a fit of rage. With a severed head placed inside a Louis Vuitton bag, the two elderly women together set off an adventure to find Chedeng's ex-girlfriend. It stars Gloria Diaz, Elizabeth Oropesa and Anthony Falcon.</strong></p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/53e3a5e5-c033-4146-bd45-8b8e7cdf238c.jpg">,<p><strong>When she learns about her terminal illness, faded and forgotten actress Delia has to find family to take care and leave her difficult husband Sammy with, before she dies in comedy-drama film “Delia and Sammy.” Directed by Therese Cayaba, the film features Rosemarie Gil, Jaime Fabregas, and Nico Antonio.</strong></p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/955dd008-9844-4e20-850a-93f0111f3637.jpg">,<p><strong>In “Gusto Kita With All My Hypothalamus,” director Dwein Baltazar explores the intertwined fate of four men, who all long for a mysterious girl named Aileen. Actors Nicco Manalo, Dylan Ray Talon, Soliman Cruz and Anthony Falcon bring this romantic film to life.</strong></p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/fed4bbf1-2b50-4d1d-ba8f-b7e85fcf0893.jpg">,<p><strong>“Mga Mister ni Rosario” by Alpha Habon is about Yogi Juan, the Philippine Showbiz’s Golden Boy who takes every role seriously, and his devoted housewife Sari who supports him and role-plays along. But what will happen when Yogi takes the role is a serial killer, can Sari revise the morbid fate that awaits her? he film stars Joross Gamboa, Kate Alejandrino, Kim Molina, Dax Carnay, Rap Robes, and Kiki Baento.</strong></p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/593f55f3-920c-471e-9a54-e30a8d12048b.jpg">,<p><strong>In “Smaller and Smaller Circles” by Raya Martin, a serial killer in Payatas leaves the bodies of young boys in the dump as two Jesuit priests try to solve the murders. Adapted from the award-winning novel of F.H. Batacan, it features Nonie Buencamino, Sid Lucero, Carla Humphries, Gladys Reyes, Raffy Tejada, Bembol Rocco, and TJ Trinidad.</strong></p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/347a3a74-2a39-4021-957b-c5ad0d2defb7.jpg">,<p><strong>Director Shireen Seno gives voice to eight-year-old Yael who prefers to be by herself, yet deeep down longs to be heard in “Nervous Translation.” In the film, the shy young girl prefers writing letters instead of performing dances. When she hears an advertisement for a pen that will give her a wonderful life, she decides to spend all her savings to buy it.</strong></p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/3f26bd42-dcb7-4788-a96f-c1f93d0089fd.jpg">,<p><strong>Directed by Kyle Fermindoza, “Manggagarab” tells about father Gabriel and daughter Celie who has been living peacefully in the mountains. Even though he struggles to provide for his daughter, everything seems normal until the past starts crawling in and devouring Gabriel.</strong></p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/8ba0e4be-ad8a-4fa8-9bd5-4797385e8c1e.jpg">,<p><strong>In “Bomba,” actor Allen Dizon plays a deaf-mute in his 40s who is having an affair with a 16-year-old girl (played by Angeli Nicole Sanoy). Director Ralston Gonzales Jover captures the deafening silent existence that is dying to explode.</strong></p>,<p><strong>Watch all these indie films at the Cinemalaya, happening on August 3 to 12, at the CCP theaters. For more information, visit <a href="http://www.cinemalaya.org/">www.cinemalaya.org</a> or <a href="http://www.culturalcenter.gov.ph./">www.culturalcenter.gov.ph.</a> You may also call CCP Media Arts at 832-1125 local 1704 to 1705 and the CCP Box Office at 832-3704. Or follow the Cinemalaya Facebook and Instagram accounts.</strong></p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/adaeba38-1796-487d-b643-c715d30d6017.jpg">]]></description>
            <link>http://thefilmdreamacademy.com/cinemalaya-features-citizen-jake-smaller-and-smaller-circle/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">89239902-fa60-4352-98a1-d7845b718df1</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 03:42:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FEATURED DOCUMENTARY FILMS AT THE CINEMALAYA’S DOKYU]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>PRESS RELEASE</strong></p>,<p><strong>July 31, 2018</strong></p>,<h1><strong>FEATURED DOCUMENTARY FILMS AT THE CINEMALAYA’S DOKYU</strong></h1>,<p><strong>ON its 14th edition, the Cinemalaya Philippine Independent Film Festival brings together a myriad of films in various genres, catering to different cinematic preferences and experiences. In Dokyu, its special documentary segment, the film festival curates six documentary films such as “Call Her Ganda,” “50 Years Of Fabulous,” “Life Is What You Make It,” “A Piece Of Paradise,” “Yield,” and “Honor, The Legacy Of Jose Abad Santos.”</strong></p>,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/bddd3ddd15aa8a5bbd87d9984147620e54e111fa.jpg">,<p><strong>In “Call Her Ganda,” director PJ Raval documents the case of Jennifer Laude, the Filipino transwoman who was brutally murdered by a US Marine. Three women intimately invested in the case - Virgie Suarez who is an activist attorney, Meredith Talusan who is a transgender journalist, Julita Laude, the mother of the slain, galvanize a political uprising, pursuing justice and taking on hardened histories of U.S. imperialism.</strong></p>,<p><strong>The documentary won the Grand Jury Award Outstanding Documentary at the Los Angeles Asian Pacific Film Festival, and the Best Documentary Audience Award at the Inside Out Toronto LGBT Film Festival.</strong></p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/58f566bb-fd12-4f29-881d-c676c662d8dc.jpg">,<p><strong>Directed by Jethro Cuenca Patalinghug, “50 Years of Fabulous” recounts the rich history of the Imperial Council, the oldest LGBT charity organization in the world. Founded in San Francisco by renown activist, drag queen and performer Jose Sarria, the Council has helped shaped LGBT life and social history in San Francisco and beyond throughout the last five decades.</strong></p>,<p><strong>The film captures the full scope of the organization’s historical evolution, as well as its contemporary struggle in finding relevance - both in the wake of the social progress it has helped foster and in light of a recently empowered political coalition committed to rolling back a half-century of civil rights achievements. The documentary premiered at the 11th Annual QDoc Film Festival in Portland.</strong></p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/dbd9ecb2-6ff0-4709-9c8e-919be4d9ce25.jpg">,<p><strong>Director-producer Jhett Tolentino shares his humble beginning from the slums of Iloilo City, Philippines to the glittery life on Broadway in “Life Is What You Make It.” The 40-minute documentary follows Tolentino’s journey as he shares his triumphant immigrant story and captures the special moments of his homecoming that is full of surprises, love, hope and inspiration.</strong></p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/3ec322aa-655d-4479-a129-0661ed9dc438.jpg">,<p><strong>“A Piece of Paradise” by Patrick Alcedo follows the everyday life of Norlyn, Em-Em, and Betsy who navigate living and working in Toronto while hoping they can visit the Philippines again. Their struggles are real but the women are resilient, knowing that their faith, community and their sense of humor will help them through the challenges. When your heart is torn between two places you love, how do you find your piece of paradise? The documentary won the National Bank Best First Feature Film and Centennial Best Canadian Film at the Toronto Reel Asian International Film Festival in 2017.</strong></p>,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/eb656d7288bdf586cc3e95f5ea358a03fd9ce275.jpg">,<p><strong>“Yield” is an ethnographic inquiry done by Toshihiko Uriu and Victor Delotavo Tagaro over a period of five years, documenting the lives of nine children living in dire Third World conditions. It was named Best Documentary at the 2018 URIAN Awards, and the Best Documentary Feature Film and Best Editing for Victor Tagaro at the 2018 FAMAS.</strong></p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/9545021c-4012-4cfe-b3d6-6eae4e89b3a2.jpg">,<p><strong>Learn about the life and legacy of the greatest Filipino hero of World War II, Chief Justice Jose Abad Santos in “Honor, The Legacy of Jose Abad Santos.” Directed by Bani Logroño, the 70-minute documentary weaved his life story with interviews from his descendants, top World War 2 Philippine historians, official documents, and excerpts from articles written by Abad Santos' son Pepito, who was with his father through his last days. Actors Dan Sheneill, Angeli Dione Gomez, Alex Medina, Marlon Mance, Marina Benipayo, and Ricardo Cepeda bring Abad's colorful life to the spotlight.</strong></p>,<p><strong>There will also be a special screening of “Journeyman Finds Home: The Simone Rota Story,” a documentary by Albert Almendralejo and Maricel Cariaga. The film chronicles the fascinating life of Philippine Azkal football player Simone Rota. It will be screened on August 8, 3:30pm at the Tanghalang Manuel Conde.</strong></p>,<p><strong>Catch these documentary films at the Cinemalaya, happening on August 3 to 12, at the CCP theaters. For more information, visit <a href="http://www.cinemalaya.org/">www.cinemalaya.org</a> or <a href="http://www.culturalcenter.gov.ph./">www.culturalcenter.gov.ph.</a> You may also call CCP Media Arts at 832-1125 local 1704 to 1705 and the CCP Box Office at 832-3704. Or follow the Cinemalaya Facebook and Instagram accounts.</strong></p>]]></description>
            <link>http://thefilmdreamacademy.com/featured-documentary-films-at-the-cinemalayas-dokyu/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2847284b-aff5-403a-aec3-a2ea2cb96ba2</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 14:21:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CINEMALAYA’S VISIONS OF ASIA PRESENTS AWARD-WINNING NETPAC AND ASIAN INDIE FILMS]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>PRESS RELEASE</strong></p>,<p><strong>July 27, 2018</strong></p>,<h1><strong>CINEMALAYA’S VISIONS OF ASIA PRESENTS AWARD-WINNING NETPAC AND ASIAN INDIE FILMS</strong></h1>,<p>THE Visions of Asia, one of the main components of Cinemalaya Philippine Independent Film Festival, presents seven award-winning Asian indie films from India, Japan, Russia, China, Thailand, and the Philippines, to be screened on August 3 to 12, 2018, at various CCP theaters.</p>,<p>The featured films include: “Beti” by P. Sheshadri, “Goodbye, Grandpa!” by Yukihiro Morogaki, “Nearest &amp; Dearest” by Kseniya Zueva, “The Taste Of Rice Flower” by Pengfei, “Of Love &amp; Law” by Hikaru Toda, “Bad Genius” by Nattawut Poonpiriya, and “The Chanters” by James Robin Mayo.</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/8c463344-cdf6-4719-96f9-0afa95d403c2.jpg">,<p>Directed and written by P. Sheshadri, “Beti” follows the story of Suleiman and his wife Juleka. While Suleiman had gone off to work overseas immediately after marriage, his wife Juleka gave birth to their daughter, Salma. But for fear of disappointment, Suleiman was made to believe that they had a son named Salman. For years, Suleiman was unable to visit Juleka and the child, so when the news came of Suleiman’s impending return, the whole household is thrown into panic. The 101-minute long film won the NETPAC Award-Best Kannada Film at the 10th Bangaluru International Film Festival in 2018.</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/be6bee35-f7f2-44db-8cf2-8c19cbf6b3df.jpg">,<p>In “Goodbye, Grandpa!” by Yukihiro Morogaki, Yoshiko receives a phone call about her grandfather’s death. On the day of the funeral, the family attended - a slovenly uncle, an angry aunt, a shut-in cousin and grandma with dementia. Yoshiko marvels that nobody cries, and she witnesses her family’s adverse behavior like never before. The film, which stars Yukino Kishii, Ryo Iwamatsu, Ken Mitsuishi, Jun Miho, and Miki Mizuno, won the NETPAC Award at the Black Nights Film Festival held in Estonia in 2017.</p>,<p>Starring Russian actors Andrei Stoyanov, Elena Chekmazova, Nadezhda Ivanova, Danila Mozhaev and Larisa Morozova, “Nearest &amp; Dearest” by Kseniya Zueva follows the story of a family who lives in a small apartment in Moscow. Each family member carries a baggage of problems that torments and requires relief. Each of them dreams of support and human warmth, but finds neither one nor the other. Life seems completely unbearable, and the defenseless old woman, living in a separate room, becomes a scapegoat. It won NETPAC Award -“Pacific Meridian” at the Vladivostok International Film Festival in 2017.</p>,<img src="https://imgflo.herokuapp.com/graph/2b2431f8e7ba7b0/ecde9a184a25fad92b5b4115c086cf42/croprotate.jpg?cropheight=3300&cropwidth=2330&degrees=0&input=https%3A%2F%2Fthe-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2F24339e45-7c4a-4b7f-8596-8ea50752d5b2.jpg&x=0&y=0">,<p>In “The Taste of Rice Flower,” director Pengfei narrates the story of Ye Nan, a mother from the Dai minority who returns to her village in Yunnan after years of working in town. She wants to take care of her rebellious-teen aged daughter, who she had left behind. However, the road to rebuild their relationship and reconnect is met with challenges and struggles as they contend with social norms and cultural traditions.</p>,<p>The Chinese film, which received the NETPAC Award at the Vesoul International Film Festival for Asian Cinema in 2018, will be the closing film of the Cinemalaya film festival on August 11, 9p.m., at the CCP Main Theater.</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/5cb9291b-24b0-4e80-aa59-9aee88cb4225.jpg">,<p>“Of Love &amp; Law” by Hikaru Toda centers on Fumi and Kazu who are partners in love and law. They run the first law firm in Japan set up by an openly gay couple. As lawyers driven by their own experience of being an outsider, they attract a range of clients who reveal the hidden diversity of a country that prides itself for collective obedience, politeness and conformity. The 94-minute long documentary features Kazuyuki Minami, Masafumi Yoshida, Yae Minami, Kazuma Tsujitani, Rokudenashiko, Hiroko Tsujitani, Masae Ido, and Natsuo Yamamoto.</p>,<p>Inspired by true events, “Bad Genius” by Nattawut Poonpiriya bis a story about Lynn, a genius high school student who makes money by cheating tests. She gets a new lucrative task that leads her to Sydney, Australia where she must take the international test and deliver the answers back home before the exam commences there. But she needs another genius, Bank, to pull off this difficult task. How far will she go to convince him? How bad will this genius become? It stars Chutimon Chuengcharoensukying, Chanon Santinatornkul, Teeradon Supapunpinyo, and Eisaya Hosuwan.</p>,<p>“The Chanters” is a comedy-drama film about Sarah Mae, a 12 year old school girl who is the grand-daughter of the last chanter of the Panay Bukidnon tribe. As her Lolo starts losing his precious memories, Sarah Mae is tasked to help him complete the last of the remaining 12 epics, their tribe’s vanishing tradition. Featuring Jally Nae Gabaliga, Romulo Caballero, Zuellen Faye Cerbo, Jean Aubrey Garin, Kara Francine Bela-Ong, the film won the Pylon Award, Best Screenplay and Best Actress at the QCinema International Film Festival, 2017.</p>,<p>“Beti,” “Goodbye Grandpa!,” Nearest &amp; Dearest,” and “The Taste of Rice Flower” are curated by NETPAC (Network for the Promotion of Asia Pacific Cinema), a worldwide organization founded in 1990 to promote a greater understanding and appreciation of Asian films and filmmakers at a time when Asian cinema was just coming into its own but was relatively unknown regionally and internationally. In 2015, the NETPAC committee has decided to expand its geographical landscape up to the Pacific Region.</p>,<p>“Of Love and Law” is in partnership with Eiga Sai, the Japanese film festival, through the Japan Foundation Manila and the Embassy of Japan in the Philippines. Meanwhile, the screening of “Bad Genius” is made possible through the partnership with the Embassy of Thailand.</p>,<p>Visions of Asia is part of the Cinemalaya Independent Film Festival, a project of the Cinemalaya Foundation, Inc. and the Cultural Center of the Philippines. Established in 2005, Cinemalaya is an all-digital film festival and competition that aims to discover, encourage and honor cinematic works of Filipino filmmakers. This year’s Cinemalaya will be held on August 3 to 12, at the CCP theaters and Ayala Malls Cinemas.</p>,<p>For more information, visit <a href="http://www.cinemalaya.org/">www.cinemalaya.org</a> or <a href="http://www.culturalcenter.gov.ph./">www.culturalcenter.gov.ph.</a> You may also call CCP Media Arts at 832-1125 local 1704 to 1705 and the CCP Box Office at 832-3704. Or follow the Cinemalaya Facebook and Instagram accounts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://thefilmdreamacademy.com/cinemalayas-visions-of-asia-presents-award-winning-netpac-a/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6e8f2ce3-584d-4265-a243-4b97b8acab4b</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 07:05:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["PORMALIN" Official Trailer]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<iframe src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2F2Rfk-2F8gBw%3Ffeature%3Doembed&url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3D2Rfk-2F8gBw&image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2F2Rfk-2F8gBw%2Fhqdefault.jpg&key=a715cf41cc93453ca338d350cd26f87b&type=text%2Fhtml&schema=youtube" width="640" height="360" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>]]></description>
            <link>https://youtu.be/2Rfk-2F8gBw</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">bfa0fc9c-3fc3-470b-b446-edda4ae724f1</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 13:51:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CCP PRESENTS THE 14TH CINEMALAYA THIS AUGUST]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>PRESS RELEASE</strong></p>,<p>July 1, 2018</p>,<h1><strong>CCP PRESENTS THE 14TH CINEMALAYA THIS AUGUST</strong></h1>,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/1eef33cc1770a323334a16e8e334fd6954705abc.jpg" title="Cinemalaya 2018 Full-length Film Directors" alt="Photo courtesy of The Film Dream">,<p>The Cultural Center of the Philippines and the Cinemalaya Foundation are set to roll out the red carpet for the 14th edition of the country's biggest independent film festival, the Cinemalaya Philippine Independent Film Festival, on August 3 to 12, 2018, at various venues of the CCP and selected Ayala Cinemas.</p>,<p>The 2018 Cinemalaya Philippine Independent Film Festival promises to deliver the best visual storytelling to every film enthusiast. Judging by this year's line-up of full-length films and short features, there is something that will surely capture the audience's imagination.</p>,<p>Following the theme “Wings of Vision,” this year's Cinemalaya will screen 10 full-length films, all competing for the grand awards. The competing full-length entries are: “Distance” by Percival Intalan; “Kung Paano Hinihintay ang Dapithapon (Waiting for Sunset)” by Carlo Enciso Catu; “Kuya Wes” by James Robin Mayo; “Liway” by Kip Oebanda; “Mamang” by Denise O'Hara; “ML” by Benedicto Mique Jr.; “Musmos na Sumibol sa Gubat ng Digma (Unless the Water is Safer than the Land)” by Iar Lionel Arondaing; “Pan De Salawal (The Sweet taste of Salter Bread and Undies)” by Che Espiritu; “School Service” by Luisito Lagdameo Ignacio; and, “The Lookout” by Afi Africa.</p>,<p>On its 14th run, there will be 10 short films, including: “Babylon” by Keith Deligero; “Jodilerks Dela Cruz, Employee of the Month” by Carlo Francisco Manatad; “Kiko” by Jojo Driz; “Logro” Kani Villaflor; “Nangungupahan (Who Rents There Now?)” by Glenn Barit; “Sa Saiyang Isla (In His Island)” by Christian Candelaria; “Si Astri maka Si Tambulah (Astri and Tambulah)” by Xeph Suarez; “Siyudad sa Bulawan (City of Gold)” by Jarell Serencio; “Yakap” by Mika Fabella and Rafael Froilan Jr.; and, “You, Me and Mr. Wiggles” by Jav Velasco.</p>,<p>Audiences will continue to enjoy the festival's mainstays: Dokyu, the documentary section; Best of the Festivals, which showcases the best films from local festivals; Indie Nation, a special section featuring independent films; Visions of Asia, featuring award-winning Asian and Netpac films. There will also be a showcase of the final projects of the Directing and Production Management workshops under the 4th Cinemalaya Institute.</p>,<p>Cinemalaya will pay tribute to Maryo J. Delos Reyes through a special screening of his best films “Bagets” and “Magnifico”; and to Bernardo Bernardo by showing “Manila by Night” by Ishmael Bernal. Retrospective section will feature the 2017 Cinemalaya Best Film “Respeto” by Treb Monteras, and “Baconaua” by Joseph Israel Laban who won Best Director.</p>,<p>On its 30th edition, the Gawad CCP Para sa Alternatibong Pelikula at Video, considered the longest-running independent film competition of its kind in the ASEAN region, will once again harvest the best of the best, with films competing in various categories such as Short Feature/Narrative, Experimental, Documentary and Animation. Pre-selected entries will be screened on August 4-6 at the CCP Tanghalang Manuel Conde (Dream Theater).</p>,<p>The Cinemalaya Campus, a major component of Cinemalaya, is slated on August 7 &amp; 8 at the Silangan Hall. The Cinemalaya Awards Night will be held on August 12, 2018 at the Tanghalang Nicanor Abelardo (CCP Main Theater).</p>,<p>Since 2005, Cinemalaya has continued to discover, encourage and support the cinematic works of upcoming and veteran Filipino filmmakers who boldly articulate and freely interpret the Philippine experience with fresh insight and artistic integrity.</p>,<p>To date, Cinemalaya has supported and promoted the production of Filipino full feature independent films and short films. Many of these films have won awards in local and international competitions and festivals. Through the annual festival, Cinemalaya has showcased over 1,000 works by independent filmmakers including full feature films, shorts, documentaries, Filipino film classics, and art films.</p>,<p>For more information about Cinemalaya, visit <a href="http://www.cinemalaya.org/">www.cinemalaya.org</a>, <a href="http://www.culturalcenter.gov.ph/">www.culturalcenter.gov.ph</a> and the Cinemalaya Facebook page or CCP Media Arts at telephone number 832-1125 local 1704 &amp; 1712 and the CCP Box Office at 832-3704.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://thefilmdreamacademy.com/cinemalaya-16-full-length-film-directors/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ff295b7e-0ccc-4337-a082-476c5a22d4ba</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 22:28:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CCP-NCCA BRINGS AKAPELA OPEN WORKSHOPS IN THE REGIONS]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>PRESS RELEASE</strong></p>,<p><strong>June 22, 2018</strong></p>,<h1><strong>CCP-NCCA BRINGS AKAPELA OPEN WORKSHOPS IN THE REGIONS</strong></h1>,<p>THE Cultural Center of the Philippines (CCP) in cooperation with the National Commission for Culture and the Arts (NCCA) bring to the regions a three-day in depth workshop on contemporary a cappella singing and music arranging intended for regional a cappella singers and groups, facilitated by a team of experts led by 2004 Gawad CCP Para sa Sining Awardee Ryan Cayabyab.</p>,<p>The regional workshops will have three legs: Mindanao in Ozamiz City on July 5-7; Luzon in Malolos City on July 12-14; and Visayas in Bacolod City on July 26-28. It is intended to promote the love for contemporary a cappella and appreciation for vocal harmony performance; make available growth experiences for singers and arrangers; and cultivate a community of contemporary a cappella singers. The workshop comprises of a lecture, clinic and samples of performances by top contemporary a cappella group/s in the country.</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/16eeb7f9-c4df-4668-9980-de9150279621.jpg" title="                            " alt="Mr. Ryan Cayabyab">,<p>Lead Facilitator Ryan Cayabyab says “This workshop will not only open the eyes of the participants to the most important elements of contemporary a cappella performance, but also the techniques in arranging that lead to creative and exciting a cappella musical scores. As a music director and composer it is important that I reach out and share my knowledge to the singers and musicians in the local communities”. Also facilitating are some of the faculty of the Music School of Ryan Cayabyab together with the <strong>Acapellago</strong> who will likewise give a special performance during the culminating program.</p>,<p>The CCP thru its Cultural Exchange Department (CED) is implementing this project in partnership with the The Music School of Ryan Cayabyab, La Salle University Ozamiz, Provincial Government of Bulacan, Sining Bulakenyo, University of St. La Salle Bacolod City and the Negros Cultural Foundation.</p>,<p>For more information, contact the CCP CED at tel. no. 832-1125 locals 1708-1709 and email address ccp.ced2014@gmail.com.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://thefilmdreamacademy.com/97881663-da8a-453c-8f98-570d3208673d/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">97881663-da8a-453c-8f98-570d3208673d</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 03:46:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TIRADA PUBLIC PROGRAMS AT CCP]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>PRESS RELEASE </strong></p>,<p><strong>June 22, 2018</strong></p>,<h1><strong>TIRADA PUBLIC PROGRAMS AT CCP</strong></h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/0c21f9b6-cb55-469c-ae37-e6dd9c52e9b7.jpg">,<p>THE Cultural Center of the Philippines and the Association of Pinoyprintmakers will conduct upcoming public programs in line with the Tirada exhibition. The roundtable discussions, which involve the intricacies and technologies in the production of fine art prints, are open to the public.</p>,<p>On June 30 (Saturday, 2-4pm) Printmaking as a moment in modernism and contemporary art will be held together with visual artists Ivi Avellana-Cosio, Fil Delacruz, Jess Flores, Raul Isidro, Rhoda Recto, and moderated by Virgilio Aviado. At 4-6pm, Printmaking as a distinct form will take place with artists Joey Cobcobo, Hershey Malinis, and Jun-Jun Sta. Ana, moderated by Angelo Magno.</p>,<p>Come July 7 (Saturday, 2-4pm), Printmaking's potency and potential will be discussed together with visual artists Ambie Abaño, Jose Santos Ardivilla, and Imelda Cajipe-Endaya. The event will be moderated by Patrick D. Flores.</p>,<p>The exhibition TIRADA: 50 Years of Philippine Printmaking 1968-2018 is on view at the CCP Buwagang Juan Luna (Main Gallery), Pasilyo Guillermo Tolentino (3F Hallway Gallery) and Pasilyo Vicente Manansala (2F Hallway Gallery) until 15 July 2018.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://thefilmdreamacademy.com/tirada-public-programs-at-ccp/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">bf7fe7b2-1ceb-42fb-a310-9c09c7937201</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 04:09:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PIANIST CLEMENT ACEVEDO OPENS CCP SPECIAL CONCERT SERIES IN JULY]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>PRESS RELEASE </strong></p>,<p><strong>June 19, 2018</strong></p>,<h1><strong>PIANIST CLEMENT ACEVEDO OPENS CCP SPECIAL CONCERT SERIES IN JULY</strong></h1>,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/469256eb6e3b88fc1806430c9eb85f26455256f9.jpg" alt="Mr. Clement Acevedo">,<p>NOTED young Filipino pianist Clement Acevedo comes home after finishing his piano studies in the United States to open the CCP Special Concert Series on Wednesday, July 25, 2018 at 7:30 PM at the Tanghalang Aurelio Tolentino. Acevedo will also give a piano masterclass at the Tanghalang Aurelio Tolentino on July 26, 2018 at 1:00 PM.</p>,<p>Pianist with “a biting rhythmic drive,” Acevedo has performed in China, the Philippines, and the United States. He was First Prize Winner of the 2004 National Music Competitions for Young Artists (NAMCYA), Piano Category C, and semi-finalist of the 2009 Heida Hermanns International Piano Competition. He has appeared as a soloist of the Metro Manila Concert Orchestra, UST Symphony Orchestra, and James Madison University Symphony Orchestra. An enthusiastic chamber musician, he has been invited to perform in professional music festivals in the Philippines and abroad.</p>,<p>Acevedo earned degrees from the University of the Philippines, Temple University, West Chester University of Pennsylvania, and James Madison University where he taught as a graduate teaching assistant/fellow. His academic career has allowed him the opportunity to be a performer, scholar, educator, and administrator. An avid administrator and artistic visionary, he serves as the president-elect of Harrisonburg Music Teachers’ Association, a 40-member group which organizes monthly events which invites artists and clinicians throughout the academic year.</p>,<p>In June 2018 he joins the music faculty of University of San Agustin Conservatory of Music in Iloilo City.</p>,<p>Acevedo’s July 25 program cuts across different culture and styles: Filipino, American, Russian, German, French and Polish. These are American composer Chester Bicardi’s Incitation to Desire, Filipino composer Robin Estrada’s Pagsasanay 1 (world premiere), Russian composer Nicolai Medner’s Fairytales and other works; French composer Maurice Ravel’s La valse, German composer’s Johannes Brahms’ Klavierstücke, Op. 119 and Polish composer Frederic Chopin’s Sonata No. 3 in B minor, Op. 58.</p>,<p>Other featured artists of the CCP Special Concert Series are harpist Madeline Jane Banta on August 29 and tenor Arthur Espiritu September 26, 2018. Tickets are at P800 and P600 with 50% discount for students and 20% Senior citizens. Regular and student subscriptions for the three concerts are also available.</p>,<p>For more information about the concert please contact the Marketing Department at 832-3706. For information about the masterclass please contact the CCP Artist Training Division at 832-1125 loc. 1604/1605.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://thefilmdreamacademy.com/press-release/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">cde3a4d1-e4c5-43d0-8e5b-e50cbc13bf92</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 03:55:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><p>The 29th Gawad CCP Para sa Alternatibong Pelikula at Video, considered the longest-running independent film competition of its kind in the ASEAN region, harvests the best of the best, with films competing in various categories such as Short Feature/Narrative, Experimental, Documentary and Animation. Pre-selected entries will be screened on August 5 to 7, 2017, at the CCP.</p><img src="http://www.thefilmdream.com/image/124414437.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>http://www.thefilmdream.com/cinemalaya13.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">96f6f45b-8bd7-4d4f-919f-2fdbbfbfbf4e</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 00:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>