<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[The Film Dream Academy]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[The Film Dream Academy]]></description>
        <link>http://thefilmdreamacademy.com/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 07:11:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://thefilmdreamacademy.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 07:10:46 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Message from Direk Alfredo Ongleo of the short film "Pormalin"]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<iframe src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FY-JNvOzOz4M%3Ffeature%3Doembed&url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DY-JNvOzOz4M&image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FY-JNvOzOz4M%2Fhqdefault.jpg&key=a715cf41cc93453ca338d350cd26f87b&type=text%2Fhtml&schema=youtube" width="640" height="360" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Y-JNvOzOz4M&amp;feature=share</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">d1fbe6bf-9731-4d55-acc9-1f2957d317af</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 11:14:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CCP PRESENTS THE 14TH CINEMALAYA THIS AUGUST]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>PRESS RELEASE</strong></p>,<p>July 1, 2018</p>,<h1><strong>CCP PRESENTS THE 14TH CINEMALAYA THIS AUGUST</strong></h1>,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/1eef33cc1770a323334a16e8e334fd6954705abc.jpg" title="Cinemalaya 2018 Full-length Film Directors" alt="Photo courtesy of The Film Dream">,<p>The Cultural Center of the Philippines and the Cinemalaya Foundation are set to roll out the red carpet for the 14th edition of the country's biggest independent film festival, the Cinemalaya Philippine Independent Film Festival, on August 3 to 12, 2018, at various venues of the CCP and selected Ayala Cinemas.</p>,<p>The 2018 Cinemalaya Philippine Independent Film Festival promises to deliver the best visual storytelling to every film enthusiast. Judging by this year's line-up of full-length films and short features, there is something that will surely capture the audience's imagination.</p>,<p>Following the theme “Wings of Vision,” this year's Cinemalaya will screen 10 full-length films, all competing for the grand awards. The competing full-length entries are: “Distance” by Percival Intalan; “Kung Paano Hinihintay ang Dapithapon (Waiting for Sunset)” by Carlo Enciso Catu; “Kuya Wes” by James Robin Mayo; “Liway” by Kip Oebanda; “Mamang” by Denise O'Hara; “ML” by Benedicto Mique Jr.; “Musmos na Sumibol sa Gubat ng Digma (Unless the Water is Safer than the Land)” by Iar Lionel Arondaing; “Pan De Salawal (The Sweet taste of Salter Bread and Undies)” by Che Espiritu; “School Service” by Luisito Lagdameo Ignacio; and, “The Lookout” by Afi Africa.</p>,<p>On its 14th run, there will be 10 short films, including: “Babylon” by Keith Deligero; “Jodilerks Dela Cruz, Employee of the Month” by Carlo Francisco Manatad; “Kiko” by Jojo Driz; “Logro” Kani Villaflor; “Nangungupahan (Who Rents There Now?)” by Glenn Barit; “Sa Saiyang Isla (In His Island)” by Christian Candelaria; “Si Astri maka Si Tambulah (Astri and Tambulah)” by Xeph Suarez; “Siyudad sa Bulawan (City of Gold)” by Jarell Serencio; “Yakap” by Mika Fabella and Rafael Froilan Jr.; and, “You, Me and Mr. Wiggles” by Jav Velasco.</p>,<p>Audiences will continue to enjoy the festival's mainstays: Dokyu, the documentary section; Best of the Festivals, which showcases the best films from local festivals; Indie Nation, a special section featuring independent films; Visions of Asia, featuring award-winning Asian and Netpac films. There will also be a showcase of the final projects of the Directing and Production Management workshops under the 4th Cinemalaya Institute.</p>,<p>Cinemalaya will pay tribute to Maryo J. Delos Reyes through a special screening of his best films “Bagets” and “Magnifico”; and to Bernardo Bernardo by showing “Manila by Night” by Ishmael Bernal. Retrospective section will feature the 2017 Cinemalaya Best Film “Respeto” by Treb Monteras, and “Baconaua” by Joseph Israel Laban who won Best Director.</p>,<p>On its 30th edition, the Gawad CCP Para sa Alternatibong Pelikula at Video, considered the longest-running independent film competition of its kind in the ASEAN region, will once again harvest the best of the best, with films competing in various categories such as Short Feature/Narrative, Experimental, Documentary and Animation. Pre-selected entries will be screened on August 4-6 at the CCP Tanghalang Manuel Conde (Dream Theater).</p>,<p>The Cinemalaya Campus, a major component of Cinemalaya, is slated on August 7 &amp; 8 at the Silangan Hall. The Cinemalaya Awards Night will be held on August 12, 2018 at the Tanghalang Nicanor Abelardo (CCP Main Theater).</p>,<p>Since 2005, Cinemalaya has continued to discover, encourage and support the cinematic works of upcoming and veteran Filipino filmmakers who boldly articulate and freely interpret the Philippine experience with fresh insight and artistic integrity.</p>,<p>To date, Cinemalaya has supported and promoted the production of Filipino full feature independent films and short films. Many of these films have won awards in local and international competitions and festivals. Through the annual festival, Cinemalaya has showcased over 1,000 works by independent filmmakers including full feature films, shorts, documentaries, Filipino film classics, and art films.</p>,<p>For more information about Cinemalaya, visit <a href="http://www.cinemalaya.org/">www.cinemalaya.org</a>, <a href="http://www.culturalcenter.gov.ph/">www.culturalcenter.gov.ph</a> and the Cinemalaya Facebook page or CCP Media Arts at telephone number 832-1125 local 1704 &amp; 1712 and the CCP Box Office at 832-3704.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://thefilmdreamacademy.com/cinemalaya-16-full-length-film-directors/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ff295b7e-0ccc-4337-a082-476c5a22d4ba</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 22:28:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["PORMALIN" Official Trailer]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<iframe src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2F2Rfk-2F8gBw%3Ffeature%3Doembed&url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3D2Rfk-2F8gBw&image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2F2Rfk-2F8gBw%2Fhqdefault.jpg&key=a715cf41cc93453ca338d350cd26f87b&type=text%2Fhtml&schema=youtube" width="640" height="360" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>]]></description>
            <link>https://youtu.be/2Rfk-2F8gBw</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">bfa0fc9c-3fc3-470b-b446-edda4ae724f1</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 13:51:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CCP-NCCA BRINGS AKAPELA OPEN WORKSHOPS IN THE REGIONS]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>PRESS RELEASE</strong></p>,<p><strong>June 22, 2018</strong></p>,<h1><strong>CCP-NCCA BRINGS AKAPELA OPEN WORKSHOPS IN THE REGIONS</strong></h1>,<p>THE Cultural Center of the Philippines (CCP) in cooperation with the National Commission for Culture and the Arts (NCCA) bring to the regions a three-day in depth workshop on contemporary a cappella singing and music arranging intended for regional a cappella singers and groups, facilitated by a team of experts led by 2004 Gawad CCP Para sa Sining Awardee Ryan Cayabyab.</p>,<p>The regional workshops will have three legs: Mindanao in Ozamiz City on July 5-7; Luzon in Malolos City on July 12-14; and Visayas in Bacolod City on July 26-28. It is intended to promote the love for contemporary a cappella and appreciation for vocal harmony performance; make available growth experiences for singers and arrangers; and cultivate a community of contemporary a cappella singers. The workshop comprises of a lecture, clinic and samples of performances by top contemporary a cappella group/s in the country.</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/16eeb7f9-c4df-4668-9980-de9150279621.jpg" title="                            " alt="Mr. Ryan Cayabyab">,<p>Lead Facilitator Ryan Cayabyab says “This workshop will not only open the eyes of the participants to the most important elements of contemporary a cappella performance, but also the techniques in arranging that lead to creative and exciting a cappella musical scores. As a music director and composer it is important that I reach out and share my knowledge to the singers and musicians in the local communities”. Also facilitating are some of the faculty of the Music School of Ryan Cayabyab together with the <strong>Acapellago</strong> who will likewise give a special performance during the culminating program.</p>,<p>The CCP thru its Cultural Exchange Department (CED) is implementing this project in partnership with the The Music School of Ryan Cayabyab, La Salle University Ozamiz, Provincial Government of Bulacan, Sining Bulakenyo, University of St. La Salle Bacolod City and the Negros Cultural Foundation.</p>,<p>For more information, contact the CCP CED at tel. no. 832-1125 locals 1708-1709 and email address ccp.ced2014@gmail.com.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://thefilmdreamacademy.com/97881663-da8a-453c-8f98-570d3208673d/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">97881663-da8a-453c-8f98-570d3208673d</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 03:46:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TIRADA PUBLIC PROGRAMS AT CCP]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>PRESS RELEASE </strong></p>,<p><strong>June 22, 2018</strong></p>,<h1><strong>TIRADA PUBLIC PROGRAMS AT CCP</strong></h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/0c21f9b6-cb55-469c-ae37-e6dd9c52e9b7.jpg">,<p>THE Cultural Center of the Philippines and the Association of Pinoyprintmakers will conduct upcoming public programs in line with the Tirada exhibition. The roundtable discussions, which involve the intricacies and technologies in the production of fine art prints, are open to the public.</p>,<p>On June 30 (Saturday, 2-4pm) Printmaking as a moment in modernism and contemporary art will be held together with visual artists Ivi Avellana-Cosio, Fil Delacruz, Jess Flores, Raul Isidro, Rhoda Recto, and moderated by Virgilio Aviado. At 4-6pm, Printmaking as a distinct form will take place with artists Joey Cobcobo, Hershey Malinis, and Jun-Jun Sta. Ana, moderated by Angelo Magno.</p>,<p>Come July 7 (Saturday, 2-4pm), Printmaking's potency and potential will be discussed together with visual artists Ambie Abaño, Jose Santos Ardivilla, and Imelda Cajipe-Endaya. The event will be moderated by Patrick D. Flores.</p>,<p>The exhibition TIRADA: 50 Years of Philippine Printmaking 1968-2018 is on view at the CCP Buwagang Juan Luna (Main Gallery), Pasilyo Guillermo Tolentino (3F Hallway Gallery) and Pasilyo Vicente Manansala (2F Hallway Gallery) until 15 July 2018.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://thefilmdreamacademy.com/tirada-public-programs-at-ccp/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">bf7fe7b2-1ceb-42fb-a310-9c09c7937201</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 04:09:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PIANIST CLEMENT ACEVEDO OPENS CCP SPECIAL CONCERT SERIES IN JULY]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>PRESS RELEASE </strong></p>,<p><strong>June 19, 2018</strong></p>,<h1><strong>PIANIST CLEMENT ACEVEDO OPENS CCP SPECIAL CONCERT SERIES IN JULY</strong></h1>,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/469256eb6e3b88fc1806430c9eb85f26455256f9.jpg" alt="Mr. Clement Acevedo">,<p>NOTED young Filipino pianist Clement Acevedo comes home after finishing his piano studies in the United States to open the CCP Special Concert Series on Wednesday, July 25, 2018 at 7:30 PM at the Tanghalang Aurelio Tolentino. Acevedo will also give a piano masterclass at the Tanghalang Aurelio Tolentino on July 26, 2018 at 1:00 PM.</p>,<p>Pianist with “a biting rhythmic drive,” Acevedo has performed in China, the Philippines, and the United States. He was First Prize Winner of the 2004 National Music Competitions for Young Artists (NAMCYA), Piano Category C, and semi-finalist of the 2009 Heida Hermanns International Piano Competition. He has appeared as a soloist of the Metro Manila Concert Orchestra, UST Symphony Orchestra, and James Madison University Symphony Orchestra. An enthusiastic chamber musician, he has been invited to perform in professional music festivals in the Philippines and abroad.</p>,<p>Acevedo earned degrees from the University of the Philippines, Temple University, West Chester University of Pennsylvania, and James Madison University where he taught as a graduate teaching assistant/fellow. His academic career has allowed him the opportunity to be a performer, scholar, educator, and administrator. An avid administrator and artistic visionary, he serves as the president-elect of Harrisonburg Music Teachers’ Association, a 40-member group which organizes monthly events which invites artists and clinicians throughout the academic year.</p>,<p>In June 2018 he joins the music faculty of University of San Agustin Conservatory of Music in Iloilo City.</p>,<p>Acevedo’s July 25 program cuts across different culture and styles: Filipino, American, Russian, German, French and Polish. These are American composer Chester Bicardi’s Incitation to Desire, Filipino composer Robin Estrada’s Pagsasanay 1 (world premiere), Russian composer Nicolai Medner’s Fairytales and other works; French composer Maurice Ravel’s La valse, German composer’s Johannes Brahms’ Klavierstücke, Op. 119 and Polish composer Frederic Chopin’s Sonata No. 3 in B minor, Op. 58.</p>,<p>Other featured artists of the CCP Special Concert Series are harpist Madeline Jane Banta on August 29 and tenor Arthur Espiritu September 26, 2018. Tickets are at P800 and P600 with 50% discount for students and 20% Senior citizens. Regular and student subscriptions for the three concerts are also available.</p>,<p>For more information about the concert please contact the Marketing Department at 832-3706. For information about the masterclass please contact the CCP Artist Training Division at 832-1125 loc. 1604/1605.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://thefilmdreamacademy.com/press-release/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">cde3a4d1-e4c5-43d0-8e5b-e50cbc13bf92</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 03:55:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><p>The 29th Gawad CCP Para sa Alternatibong Pelikula at Video, considered the longest-running independent film competition of its kind in the ASEAN region, harvests the best of the best, with films competing in various categories such as Short Feature/Narrative, Experimental, Documentary and Animation. Pre-selected entries will be screened on August 5 to 7, 2017, at the CCP.</p><img src="http://www.thefilmdream.com/image/124414437.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>http://www.thefilmdream.com/cinemalaya13.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">96f6f45b-8bd7-4d4f-919f-2fdbbfbfbf4e</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 00:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><img src="http://thefilmdream.com/image/104969123_scaled_354x516.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>http://thefilmdream.com/the-fury-road-of-george-miller.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">04b4b20c-fc54-46ab-a61f-63706b800833</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2017 03:13:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/29b399ff6669a859931c46765a78c862a8f06875.jpg">]]></description>
            <link>http://www.fdcp.ph/contents/news?id=Hele%20sa%20Hiwagang%20Hapis%20Returns%20to%20the%20Cinematheques%20this%20April</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">1c896d13-7b2f-48b0-a09d-c1af33e84cd3</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2017 03:19:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><img src="http://thefilmdream.com/image/106806829_scaled_350x519.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>http://thefilmdream.com/southpaw-how-billy-hope-made-me-cry.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2d7bafc3-5382-4014-aef7-90021f126139</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2017 03:13:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>